셜록, 또 시작됐어요
Sherlock, they're at it again!
Hey.
내 말 들려요?
Hey, can you hear me?
헤드폰 빼도 돼요
You can remove my headphones!
옆집 사람들 또 시작했어요
The people next door
are at it again.
또? 그만 둔 줄도 몰랐는데
Again?
I wasn't aware they stopped.
-3일 연속이잖아요
-알아요
This is the third night in a row.
I know.
당신의 수면 시간이
너무 많은 것도 알아요
I also know that you spend
far too much time in slumber.
내 충고를 원한다면,
방해의 혜택을
If you want my advice,
you should take advantage
받아들여서 잠을 포기하고
of this disturbance,
forgo sleep,
당신의 능력을 시험하는
활동을 찾아요
and find an activity
which tests your abilities.
예를 들면, 정교한
억제구에서 탈출이라든지
Escaping elaborate restraints,
for example.
저게 방해가 안되면 소음차단
헤드폰을 쓰는 이유가 뭔데요?
If that doesn't bother you, then
why did you choose an activity
that included
noise-canceling headphones?
소음에 영향을 받지
않는다고는 안했어요
I didn't say I was
impervious to the noise,
자극제로 이용하라고 말했지
I merely said
I was using it as an impetus.
리듬에 집착하는 이웃은
곧 그만둘 거예요
In any case, our rhythm-obsessed
neighbor should be done soon.
특정 리프를 익히려고 노력중이지만
He's been trying to master
a particular riff,
마지막 시도에서 성공했다고 생각해요
and I think that last attempt
was successful.
Yeah.
거봐요
You can safely resume
your nightly rituals.
무사히 밤의 의식을 치를 수 있겠네요
저기
Could...
No, that's not...
아니 됐어
????
자연은 우리에게 많은 기적을 내려요
Nature provides us
with so many wonders.
하지만 나에게는
이게 가장 큰 축복이죠
But for me,
this is her greatest gift.
실로시빈
Psilocybin.
버섯에서 얻어지는 천연유래성분으로
A naturally-occurring compound
found in simple mushrooms,
which can open our minds
우리 마음을 열고
영혼의 영역에 도달할 수 있고
to the realm of spirit,
allowing us
영원을 맛보게 허락해줘요
to touch the eternal.
Unfortunately, the mushrooms
themselves taste like crap.
불행히도, 버섯 자체의 맛은 지독해요
하지만 맛이나
But the taste
오심, 불편감을 느끼는 것도
and any nausea or discomfort
that you feel--
또 하나의 경험이죠
that's part of the
experience, too.
I'll be with you
every step of the way.
매 단계마다 제가 함께 있을 겁니다
To the journey.
여행을 위하여
효과가 나타나려면
보통 30분 정도 걸려요
The effects usually take
about 30 minutes.
The first thing
you will probably notice...
아마 처음 알게되는...
저건 체험의 일부가 아닙니다
That is not
part of your experience.
이웃에 사는 멍청이죠
That is my oaf
of a neighbor.
내가 해결할게요
I will take care of that.
채드, 비디오게임하는 동안
Chad, might I ask you
to, uh,
헤드폰을 사용해줄래요?
don headphones
while you play your video games?
체험을 주최하고 있어서요
I'm hosting an experience.
그러죠
Sure.
나한테도 마법의 차를 가져다준다면
As long as you save
a little magic tea for me.
더이상 방해하지 않으면
Uh, I'll bring you
a to-go cup in the morning
아침에 가져다줄게요
if there are
no further disruptions.
내가 말했듯이, 한두번 토하지 않고는
As I said, the universe
rarely allows enlightenment
without throwing up
a challenge or two.
우주가 쉽게 환희를 제공하지 않아요
Oh, no.
No!
안돼
911입니다. 무슨 일이십니까?
911. Where's the emergency?
여보세요? 누구 없어요?
Hello? Is anyone there?
# Elementary 4x13 #
A Study in Charlotte
Original Air Date on February 18, 2016
??Elementary 4x13 ??/font>
A View With a Room
Original Air Date on February 18, 2016
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
마약 파티가 잘못된 모양이야
Uh, looks like
a drug party gone wrong.
조셉 발렌타인,
QBU의 식물학 교수지
That's Joseph Ballantine,
botany professor at QBU.
이웃 말로는 일년에
2번정도 버섯 파티를 연대
Neighbor says he throws
these mushroom parties
a couple times a year.
파티라
Some party.
이번엔 버섯을 잘못 골라서
Yeah, I figure he picked the
wrong 'shrooms this time around,
본인과 고객이 모두 독살됐어
poisoned himself
and his customers.
Uh, wrong.
틀려요
That's some consultant
from Major Cases.
강력반 자문탐정이래
그냥 나타났어
He just showed up.
스캐너로 들었다고 하면서
Said he heard about it
on his scanner.
You made him
sit in a corner?
저기 앉아있으라고 했어?
아니, 그냥 자기가 앉던데
No, he did that himself.
증거를 훼손하고 싶지 않아요
I was asked not to disturb
any evidence.
눈을 돌리는 것도
피해야겠다 싶었고요
I thought I might also
avert my gaze.
발렌타인 교수 부분에서
실수를 했어요
Your detective believes
this to be a mistake
on Ballantine's part,
but the professor
교수는 환각 버섯 전문가예요
was an authority
on psychedelic mushrooms.
여러권의 훌륭한 저서를 남겼죠
He wrote several excellent books
on the subject.
멍청한 신비주의만 빼면
And despite
his idiotic mysticism,
뛰어난 진균학자로
환각버섯과 독버섯을
he was a peerless mycologist
who would never mistake
혼동하는 실수를
할 리가 없어요
poisonous mushrooms
for psychedelic ones.
토미 그렉슨이 5분만 시간을 주라는군
Tommy Gregson asked us
to give you five minutes.
2분 줄게요
You've got two.
As I thought.
내 생각대로
The mushrooms the professor
has in his tea
교수가 차에 넣은 버섯은
psilocybe azurescens로
'블루 엔젤'로 알려져있어요
are pure psilocybe azurescens,
also known as Blue Angels.
강하지만 상대적으로 드문 종으로
They are a potent
and relatively rare species
콜롬비아 강 삼각주에서 자생해요
native to
the Columbia River Delta.
독버섯은 아니에요
There's not a toadstool
in the pot.
And you can tell that
just by looking?
보기만 해도 말할 수 있어요?
버섯 감별은 좋은 탐정이
Identifying fungi
is one of a host of skills
가져야할 주요 기술 중 하나죠
a good detective
should have.
These people died quickly.
이 사람들 급사했어요
다양한 악취가 나오지 않아요
Note the lack of smearing
in the various effluvia.
도움을 요청하려고 비틀거리거나
No one tried to stagger for help
문을 긁은 사람도 없어요
or to crawl for the door.
쓰러져서 바로 죽었어요
They died where they fell,
고농도의 독에 노출되었다는 뜻이죠
meaning they were exposed
to a highly concentrated poison.
They were murdered.
살해됐네요
Somebody put something
in their drinks.
누군가 차에 독을 탔어요
그보다는 교수의 버섯에 독을 넣었겠죠
More likely,
someone put something
in the professor's mushrooms.
추측해야한다면,
amanita phalloides(알광대버섯)
If I had to guess, I'd say
extract of amanita phalloides,
the aptly-named
death cap mushroom.
일명 '죽음의 모자'
버섯 추출물이라고 봐요
That would make him
주요 타겟은 교수였고,
학생들은 이차 피해자였을 겁니다
the likely target
and the students
collateral damage.
다행히 동기와 용의자를 이미 알고 있으니
Fortunately, I've already got
a motive and suspect in mind,
so... it was a pleasure
meeting the both of you.
두 사람을 만나서 즐거웠어요
I'm sorry.
실례해요
제가 깨웠나요?
Did I wake you?
You must be exhausted.
지쳐보이네요. 아침 5시까지
베이스 연주하느라 힘들겠죠
You were up till what,
5:00 in the morning
playing bass?
You live next door.
옆집 사람이군요
-맞아요
-죄송해요
I do.
Sorry.
집주인이 벽이 두꺼우니까
Our landlord told us
the walls were thick
맘대로 시끄럽게 해도
괜찮다고 했거든요
and we could make
as much noise as we liked.
네, 근데 다 들려요
Yeah, well, I can
hear everything, okay?
3주전에 벌인 파티
That party you had
three weeks ago--
어린애들이 6시간동안
시끄럽게 떠들어댔잖아요
those little kids you had
screaming at each other
for six hours...
Yeah, that wasn't us.
그건 우리가 아닌데
I heard you.
다 들었어요
아뇨. 다른 사람이 파티를 했어요
Uh, no.
Someone else threw that party.
아이가 있는 다른 사람이요
And someone else
had the kids over.
We've only been
here five days.
우린 여기 5일동안 있었어요
Five days?
5일이요?
네, 에이전트랑 음악
제작자 만나러 왔거든요
Yeah. Uh, we're just in town
to meet agents
and music executives.
주말에 갈거예요
We'll be gone by
the end of the week.
그럼 새로 이사온 사람들이 아니었어요?
So you're not the new tenants?
네
No.
손님이에요?
Are you guests?
You know this place
is an AwayKay, right?
여기가 AwayKay인 건 알죠?
I-I don't know what that is.
뭔지 몰라요
민박같은 건데
It's like, um,
vacation rental.
우리 드러머가 인터넷에서 찾았어요
Our drummer
found it online.
AwayKay.com.
"파티 피플을 위한 파티장"
?Party pads for party people.??
I'm sorry about
the noise.
시끄럽게 해서 미안해요
하지만 앞으로도
계속 겪을 것 같네요
But... I think you're gonna
have to get used to it.
싸움 혹은 도주 반응은
The fight or flight response
시상하부에서 시작해서
2가지 방법으로
starts in the hypothalamus,
which activates
the adrenal gland
in two different ways.
부신을 활성화시킵니다
화학적으로는 뇌하수체를 통해
Chemically,
via the pituitary gland,
신경 자극은 척수를 따라갑니다
and with a nerve impulse
via the spinal cord.
This triggers the adrenal gland,
the release of adrenaline,
이는 부신을 자극하여
아드레날린을 분비하고
최고조에 이르게 됩니다
and that's when things
really kick into high gear.
다음주에 계속합시다
We will pick up with that
next week.
Remember to read chapter five.
5장 꼭 읽어와요
수고했어요
Thank you.
Can I help
you gentlemen?
무슨 일로 오셨습니까?
코르티졸은요?
What about cortisol?
The adrenal gland
releases two hormones--
부신은 두 개의 호르몬을 분비해요
에프네프린, 즉 아드레날린, 그리고 코르티졸
epinephrine, aka adrenaline,
but also cortisol,
두 호르몬 모두 싸움 혹은 회피
반응에 중추적 역할을 해요
and both of those
hormones are crucial
to the fight or
flight response.
다음 수업에 대한 예고였어요
I was just
teasing the next lesson.
아드레날린이 코르티졸보다 더 섹시하죠
And adrenaline is sexier
than cortisol.
Are you with
the accreditation review?
승인 검토 때문에 오셨나요?
다음 주에 올 줄 알았어요
Because I wasn't
expecting you until next week.
저희는 NYPD입니다
We're with the NYPD.
조셉 발렌타인 살인사건에 대해
We're here to ask
a few questions
몇가지 질문이 있어서 왔어요
about the murder of
Joseph Ballantine.
I always knew Joe's research
조의 연구로 인해 곤란해질
줄 알고 있었어요
might get him into trouble.
하지만 살인이라니
But murdered?
Preliminary tests indicate
예비검사에서
발렌타인 교수가 사용한 버섯에
that the mushrooms he used
were infused with poison
다른 독버섯이 섞여있었어요
from another mushroom.
The two of you wrote
두 분이 3권의 책을 저술했더군요
three books together:
two explorations
2권은 실로시빈의 생화학
효과에 대한 탐구이고
on the biochemical
effects of psilocybin
1권은 실로시빈 화학 교재였어요
and one textbook on
the chemistry of psychedelics.
Then you two had a falling out.
그리고 사이가 틀어졌죠
I wouldn't call it that.
그렇게 말할 정도는 아니었어요
Two years ago,
2년 전, 당신이 발간중인
"정신생물학 학술지"에서
you published an article
in the Northeastern Journal
of Psychobiology
repudiating his work.
조의 논문을 거절했어요
당신은 환각버섯에 대해
You called his stance
on the benefits
"위험한 비과학"이라고 평했죠
of psychedelic mushrooms
?dangerous pseudoscience.??
핵심을 제거했어요. 공동 저자로
It was an evisceration;
and it was
책을 출판했을 때와는 전혀
반대의 입장으로 돌아섰어요
a complete reversal
of the position
that the two of you took
in the books you wrote together.
그 책들은 더이상 볼 수 없어요
Those books?
Not available anymore.
시장에서 철수됐어요
Pulled from the market.
I'm assuming
that was at his request.
조의 요청때문이었겠죠
인세로 수천달러는
벌 수 있었을텐데요, 그쵸?
And that would've cost you
tens of thousands of dollars
in royalties, right?
Look...
저기
you're right that Joe and I
went our separate ways.
조와 전 각자의 길을
가기로 했다는 건 맞아요
But that was my choice.
하지만 그건 내 결정이었어요
Joe invited me
조가 먼저 같이 책을 쓰자고 했어요
to work on those books with him.
He wanted an expert
in brain chemistry.
뇌 화학 전문가를 원했어요
Part of the deal was that
I take mushrooms myself.
계약에는 내가 직접 버섯을
먹는 게 포함되어 있었어요
내가 직접 경험하기를 원했어요
He wanted me to have
first-hand experience.
But?
I didn't like
하지만?
난 실로시빈이나 다른 약을
하고 싶지 않았어요
what the psilocybin
and other drugs did to me.
I did stupid things
when I was using.
약을 했을 때는 내가 어리석었어요
I needed a
clean break.
완전히 그만두고 싶었어요
출판 중단도 내 생각이었어요
Pulling the books was my idea.
조의 이론 지지에 내 이름이
기재되지 않길 바랐어요
I didn't want my name
on anything
that endorsed Joe's theories.
How did he take that?
어떻게 받아들였나요?
He was fine.
괜찮았어요
과학 언론에 비난해도 신경쓰지 않았어요
And he didn't care when I ripped
him in the scientific press.
기존 이론에 반역자로 이미지가 딱이었죠
It fit with his image as a rebel
fighting the establishment.
So there were no hard feelings?
그래서 서로 감정이 상하지는 않았다?
Joe and I were in the
same department here.
조와 나는 같은 학부에 있어요
We ran into each
other all the time.
항상 오고가며 마주쳤어요
물어봐요. 다툼이 있었는지
Ask anyone--
there was never any trouble.
We made our peace.
우린 평화롭게 지냈어요
So what did I miss?
내가 뭘 놓쳤어요?
Professor Harper,
it seems,
하퍼 교수는,
발렌타인 교수를 살해할
동기가 전혀 없어보여요
did not have motive to kill
Professor Ballantine after all.
오, 당신이 틀렸네요
Oh, so you were wrong.
마커스가 하퍼교수의 말을 확인할 동안
While Marcus confirms
Harper's story,
발렌타인이 죽길 원했을 다른 사람에
대한 증거를 찾고 있었고
I've been casting
about for clues
as to who else might have
wanted Ballantine dead,
실패시, 버섯을 얻은 곳을 찾으려고요
and, failing that,
where he acquired
his lethal mushrooms.
Would you care
to join me?
합류할 거예요?
물론, 충분히 쉬었다면요
I mean, if you're sufficiently
rested, of course.
I wasn't sleeping in,
I was meeting our new neighbors.
자고 있었던 게 아니라,
새 이웃을 만나고 왔어요
Did you intimidate them
into silence?
조용히 하라고 협박했어요?
I did.
했어요
But it doesn't matter;
they're short-term renters.
근데 상관없는게,
단기 임대자였어요
New people are
coming in on Sunday.
일요일에 다른 사람들이 온대요
The building is advertised
on a Web site called AwayKay.
AwayKay라는 홈페이지에서 광고중이었어요
잘나가는 동네에서 파티장을 찾는
사람들을 모아주는 곳이죠
They cater to people looking for
party pads
in trendy neighborhoods.
우리 집 근처에만 5-6곳이 있어요
They have five or six locations
within a few blocks of us.
고급 주택화의 또다른 불쾌함이군요
Another unfortunate sign
of gentrification.
우리 지역 주민들의
활동을 격려해야겠어요
Perhaps we should
encourage our local muggers
to increase their activity.
문제가 있는 건 우리만은 아니겠죠
We are not the only
ones with a problem.
동네 웹사이트를 확인해보니
I checked the
neighborhood Web site,
AwayKays들에 대한
소음 불만으로 가득했어요
and it is filled
with noise complaints
about the AwayKays.
근처 호텔들도 장사가 안되고
And local hotels
are losing business.
I'm gonna talk to the owner
next door tomorrow
옆집 주인을 찾아가서
불편하다는 얘길 해야겠어요
and let him know
we are not happy.
There's a safe inside the sofa?
소파 안에 금고가 있어요?
네, 다행히 정교한 잠금 기술보다는
Yeah. One that relies
on concealment
숨기려고 했던 것 같아요
rather than a sophisticated
locking mechanism,
fortunately.
무척 간단할걸요
Should be simple enough.
There.
됐다
Professor Ballantine's stash.
발렌타인 교수의 은닉품
말린 버섯 3가지
Three bags
of dried mushrooms.
이건 저품질의 마법의 버섯이군요
These are poor quality
psilocybe cubensis.
이건 불행하게 끝났던 의식에서
사용하지 않았어요
This is not what was used
in his ill-fated ceremony.
하지만 이건 블루엔젤이에요
But these are
Blue Angels.
교수의 차에서 발견했던 것과
똑같은 품종이에요
This is the exact same
strain I found in his tea.
?Looking forward
to your thoughts. Danke.
"교수님의 견해 기대하고 있어요,
Danke. C.K”.
C.K??
I saw a manuscript
that Ballantine was proofing
발렌타인이 이끼류에 대해
입증하려던 논문들을 봤어요
about lichen.
샬롯 코니그(Charlotte Konig)라는
이름으로 쓰인 글이 있었어요
It was written by someone
named Charlotte Konig.
C.K.
If you could just wait here,
sir, and keep the meter running.
여기서 기다려주시면
미터기 계속 돌려도 돼요
Thanks.
고마워요
According to
university records,
대학교 기록에 따르면
샬롯 코니그는 독일 태생 생화학자로
Charlotte Konig
is a German-born biochemist
발렌타인의 예전 조교였어요
and Ballantine's
former teaching assistant.
Here's a photograph of her
in her student days.
학생시절의 사진이 있어요
문신을 하고 다녔죠
She's the one with the tattoos.
The lights are on. I hear music.
불이 켜져 있고, 음악소리도 들려요
Hey, maybe
we should wait
마커스가 올 때까지 기다려야해요
till Marcus gets here.
I mean, Charlotte gave
Ballantine those mushrooms.
샬롯이 발렌타인에게 버섯을 줬잖아요
She could be a murderer.
살인범일 수도 있어요
그렇다고 해도 독살범이죠
Even if she is,
she's a poisoner.
먹거나 마시지 않으면
우린 무사해요
Just don't eat or drink
anything; we should be okay.
What are you doing?
뭐해요?
I smell mushrooms.
버섯 냄새가 나요
That's really great, but, um,
훌륭해요, 하지만
택시기사 앞에서
무단침입을 하려고요?
is it really enough to break and
enter in front of our cabbie?
I smell mushrooms.
버섯 냄새가 나요
버섯 냄새...
He smells mushrooms.
# And... crazy #
??And... crazy ??
# And you think I'm putting on
some kind of act #
??And you think I'm putting on
some kind of act ??
# But this is
me, me, me, me, me #
??But this is
me, me, me, me, me ??
# And you know what's sick? #
??And you know what's sick? ??
# I kinda like it #
??I kinda like it ??
# That nobody I know... #
??That nobody I know... ??
버섯 냄새가 난다고 했잖아요
Told you
I smelled mushrooms.
독성검사 결과 "죽음의 모자"
중독으로 사망했어요
Toxicology confirms
she died from death cap poison.
누가 버섯을 뿌려놨더군요
Someone sprayed
her entire crop with the stuff.
These were growing on her?
이게 샬롯 몸에서 자랐다고?
저희 생각에는, 죽어가다가
We think,
as she was dying,
다 자란 버섯이 든 병을
쓰러뜨린 것 같아요
she knocked over a jar
of mature mushrooms.
포자를 퍼뜨렸고, 그 포자가
샬롯의 몸에 자리잡은거죠
They spored, and the spores
landed on her body.
We now think that she was
지금은 조셉 발렌타인이 아니라
샬롯이 독살범이 의도한
목표였다고 생각해요
the intended target of the
poisoner, not Joseph Ballantine.
이 사진들로 보면
As you can tell
from these photographs,
판매용으로 보기에는 수량이 너무 적어요
her crop was too small for her
to be a dealer-- she grew
자기 자신과 친구들의
선물용으로 재배했을 겁니다
just enough for her own use and
occasional gifts for friends.
Seems unlikely the
person who did it
샬롯이 발렌타인에게
버섯을 나눠줄 걸 알지는
못했던 것 같아요
would've known she
would share her crop
with Ballantine.
또한, 실로시빈 잔여물이
Also, there was
psilocybin residue
차 주전자와 컵에 남아있는 걸로 봐선
in her tea kettle and cups,
꾸준히 먹었던 것으로 보여요
which indicates
she was a regular user.
직접 버섯을 재배해서
We figure it must be
someone close to her,
꾸준히 먹는 걸 알 정도로
someone who knew
she grew her own mushrooms
샬롯과 친한 사람을 찾아야해요
and used them regularly.
아니면 샬롯에 대해 엄청 연구했겠죠
Or someone
who studied her extensively.
그렇긴해도 샬롯의 연구는
Having said that,
a study of Charlotte
간단한 노력이 아니었을 겁니다
would be no simple endeavor.
식물학과 생화학에 대해 잘 알았지만
She might have been a whiz with
botany and biochemistry, but...
-전자공학은 별로 즐기지 않았어요
-맞아요
- she was not keen on electronics.
- Yeah.
SNS도 하지 않고
심지어 휴대폰도 없어요
She didn't use social media.
Didn't even have a cell phone.
우리가 아는 건, 독일 태생으로
What we know so far is
she was born in Germany,
대학교 진학으로 미국으로 건너와
발렌타인 교수 밑에서 공부하고
came to the U.S. for college,
studied under Ballantine,
학위를 딸때까지 저연봉, 단기직
연구실 일만 이어서 했어요
then had a series of low-paying,
short-term lab jobs
since she got her degree.
개인사에 대한 또다른 단서는 문신이죠
Another clue to her personal
life might be her tattoos.
She had a lot
of them.
문신이 아주 많아요
There's a fresh griffin tattoo
on her shoulder,
어깨에는 새로 만든 그리핀 문신이 있고
목에는 옴, 팔에는 꽃이 달린
덩굴 문신이 있어요
an om on her neck,
vines on her forearm,
assorted flowers.
등에 있는 건?
What's that on her back?
부검 보고서에 사진이 있을 거예요
Uh, I think there's a
photo in the MLI's report.
“Rache.” 뭐지?
레이첼의 줄임말인가?
?Rache.??What is that,
short for Rachel?
그럴 수도 있어요
That's possible.
하지만 샬롯은 원래 독일어를 써요
But Charlotte's native language
is German.
독일어에서 “rache”는
'복수'를 뜻해요
And in German, that word is
?rache,??/i> which means ?revenge.??
밴드 이름일 수도 있고
Maybe it's the name of a band
or sulein Konig
말 그대로 코니그양이 복수를 했을 수도 있죠
craved revenge.
복수를 했다면, 그 대상자가
If she did, you got to wonder
샬롯을 죽였을지도 궁금하겠지
who killed her
to keep her from getting it.
Actually, we may already
have a pretty good idea.
실은, 벌써 좋은 생각이 있어요
Charlotte Konig
was suing your company
샬롯 코니그가 당신 회사를
상대로 1억달러 소송 중이었죠?
for $100 million, correct?
해조류를 생물연료로 바꾸는 기술을
우리가 훔쳤다고 주장했어요
She claimed we stole her process
for turning algae into biofuel.
Did you?
그랬나요?
당연히 아닙니다
Of course not.
'제라켐'에서 같은 시기에 같은 기술을
Zerakem developed
the same process she did
개발했어요. 우연의 일치입니다
at roughly the same time;
it's coincidence.
That's not how Ms. Konig saw it.
코니그 의견은 아니던데요
Her lawsuit claims
she published her process
소송에서 제라켐보다 6개월 전에
발표했다고 주장했어요
almost six months
before Zerakem announced theirs.
Your company does not have
회사가 최고의 평판을 가진 건 아니죠
the best reputation.
제라켐은 기업 스파이행위와
We've heard accusations
that Zerakem engaged
in corporate espionage, as well
as bribing government officials.
공무원 뇌물 혐의도 받고 있다고 들었어요
It's not such a great leap
샬롯 코니그를 장애물로 봤다면
제거해야한다는 생각도
to think that if you saw
Charlotte Konig as an obstacle,
you might have had her removed.
큰 일은 아니었을 겁니다
이건 샬롯 코니그의
변호사들의 철회된 발언입니다
These are denied motions
from Charlotte Konig's lawyers.
We had no reason
to kill her.
우린 샬롯을 살해할 이유가 없어요
우린 재판에서 이기고 있었어요
We were crushing her in court.
Did Charlotte ever try
샬롯이 당신이나 제라켐의 다른 사람을
to take matters
into her own hands,
협박하는 일을 직접 했나요?
threaten you or anyone else
at Zerakem?
I have no
record of that.
그런 기록은 없어요
But even if
she did try,
하지만 시도했더라도
우리가 죽일 리는 없어요
we wouldn't have her killed.
We'd get a restraining order.
가처분 명령을 받았어요
I have a question of my
own, if that's all right.
질문이 있는데, 해도 될까요
You think that Charlotte
and those other people
샬롯과 다른 사람들이 모두
'죽음의 모자'로 독살됐나요?
were killed by death cap poison?
독성검사에서 증명됐어요
Toxicology proved it.
Before I made VP,
부사장이 되기 전에
저도 생화학자로 일했어요
I worked my way up
as a biochemist,
and I know for a fact
there's no way
자연발생 죽음의 모자 독으로는
사람들이 그렇게 빨리 죽지
않는다고 알고 있어요
naturally-occurring
death cap poison
could kill those people
so quickly.
On that, we agree.
그 점에선, 동의합니다
Our current theory
is that the killer
현재 우리의 가설은 범인이
대량의 버섯에서 독소를 추출하여
extracted mycotoxin
from a large number of mushrooms
치사량으로 농축했다는 겁니다
and then concentrated it
to produce a lethal dose.
그 방법이 가능하지만
느리고 비효율적이죠
That is one way to do it,
but it's slow and inefficient.
맨 처음부터 생화학 작실에서
A better way would be
to synthesize the poison,
독을 합성하는 방법이 있을텐데요
build it up from scratch from
biochemical building blocks.
I mean, if it helps,
I could give you a list
도움이 된다면,
근처에 그런 작업이 가능한
of facilities around here
that do that kind of work.
시설 목록을 드릴 수도 있어요
Welcome.
어서오세요
If I can help you with
anything, let me know.
필요하신 게 있으면 얘기하세요
Um, actually, I was hoping
I could talk to you
실은, AwayKay에 올려놓은
건물에 대해 얘기하려고 왔어요
about the building
you turned into an AwayKay.
I remember you.
기억나요
You're the girlfriend--
Sherlock's.
셜록의 여자친구죠
Yeah, you moved in with him
about a year before I left.
내가 이사 나오기 1년 전부터 동거했죠
Uh, I'm not his girlfriend.
여자친구는 아니에요
And I didn't realize
you two knew each other.
셜록과 아는 사이인지 몰랐어요
We don't.
아니오
I introduced myself on
the day he moved in.
셜록이 이사오던 날 직접 내 소개를 했지
이름을 알고, 이메일을 받았어
Got his name, his e-mail.
That's it.
그게 전부요
AwayKay에 집을 올려놓을 생각인가요?
Are you thinking of turning
your place into an AwayKay?
It's easy.
쉬워요
I can tell you all about it.
내가 다 말해줄 수 있어요
We've been having
some problems with noise.
소음때문에 힘들어요
People coming in
at all hours. It...
들어오는 사람들이 항상
Is there something funny?
재밌어요?
I'm sorry, it's...
미안해요
That's rich,
참 재밌군요
you two
complaining about the noise.
두 사람이 소음으로 불평하다니
How so?
어째서요?
Because...
왜냐면
you're the reason that I can't
live in my own building.
내 집에서 살지 못하는 이유가 당신들이거든
You're the reason that I
can't keep tenants in there
세를 줘도 당신들 때문에
6개월이상을 버티지 못했어요
for more than six
months at a time.
You're not happy that I turned
my place into an AwayKay?
내 집을 AwayKay에 올려서 힘들다고?
Yeah, too bad.
참 안됐군요
You brought it
on yourselves.
당신들이 자초한 일이지
I don't know
what you're talking about.
무슨 말인지 모르겠어요
I moved out because of you two.
당신들 때문에 이사를 갔지
I couldn't take it anymore.
더이상 견디지 못하겠더군
이상한 소음, 수상한 냄새,
The weird noises,
the strange smells,
폭발, 옥상에는 망할 놈의 벌까지
the explosions, and the
damn bees on the roof.
오, 저런,
Oh, come on, please.
처음 듣는 얘기인 척 하지 말아요
Don't pretend that
this is news to you.
처음 들어요
Actually, it is.
Look, you didn't just
list your place on AwayKay.
AwayKay에 집을 올리는 게 문제가 아니라
You went out of your way
to attract problem tenants.
입주민을 끌기 위한 방법이죠
I read the ad. ?Parties welcome.
Noise not an issue.??
광고 읽었어요
"파티 환영, 소음 문제 없음"
This is not just about
paying the mortgage.
융자금 갚는 게 문제가 아니죠
Every action has an equal
and opposite reaction.
모든 작용에는 같은 크기의 반작용이 있지
That's physics.
물리학이라오
That's crazy.
말도 안돼요
오래 전부터 얘기를 했으면
고쳤을 수도 있어요
We could've talked about this
and fixed it a long time ago.
I e-mailed Sherlock
dozens of times.
셜록에게 이메일을
수십번을 보냈어요
I practically begged him
to be more considerate.
배려해달라고 애원하기까지 했지
But it only got worse.
하지만 더 심해지기만 했어요
And then the... the roosters--
that was the last straw.
그리고 그 수탉들이,
최후의 결정타였어요
I forgot about the roosters.
수탉은 잊고 있었어요
Yeah, I did, too.
그래, 나도 잊었어요
Eventually.
결국엔
By moving out.
이사 나오면서
Those e-mails you sent--
could you show them to me?
보내셨던 이메일,
저한테 보여주실 수 있어요?
죽음의 모자 독을 합성할 수는 있지만
I suppose we could
synthesize death cap poison,
but I can't imagine anyone
wanting to kill Charlotte.
샬롯을 죽길 원하는 사람은
떠오르지 않아요
You knew her?
아는 사이였나요?
She used to work here.
여기서 일했었어요
Until about
a year ago.
1년 전까지
다정하고, 생각하시는 것보다는
훨씬 조용한 편이죠
She was sweet, and much
quieter than you'd think.
All those tattoos.
문신 때문에요
타인과 문제를 일으킨 적 있나요?
Um, she have any issues
with anyone?
근무 일정이나 성희롱이나
Conflicts over work duties,
sexual harassment,
어느 것이든지요
anything like that?
아뇨, 제가 알기론 없어요
No, not that I'm aware of.
고마워요, 무척 도움이 됐어요
Thank you, Doctor,
you've been most helpful.
Excuse me.
저기요
Uh, I work with the police.
난 경찰과 함께 일합니다
I was hoping
we might have a chat.
얘기를 나눴으면 해서요
About?
무슨 일이죠?
About Charlotte Konig.
샬롯 코니그에 대해서요
And whether
your sleeping together
당신과의 동침이 살인에
영향을 미쳤는지 여부에 대해서요
had anything to do
with her murder.
Nobody knew about us here,
so how did you...?
이 곳 사람들은 아무도
몰랐는데, 어떻게...?
Your forearm tattoo.
팔에 있는 문신이요
It's almost identical
샬롯의 문신과 거의 같았어요
to the one that Charlotte had.
사실, 옆으로 대면
In fact, if you were
to line them up,
덩쿨이 서로 연결됐죠?
those vines would interconnect,
would they not?
그러니 둘이 연인이었죠
의심의 여지 없이
So the two of you were lovers.
That's not in any doubt.
What is in question is...
문제는...
We were together
for almost a year.
우린 거의 1년을 사귀었어요
절대 해치지 않아요
I would never have hurt her.
하지만 더이상 사귀는 사이가 아니죠
But you're not together anymore.
When we started hanging out,
she was fun.
처음 사귀기 시작했을 때
샬롯은 재밌었어요
She liked to take mushrooms,
drop acid, do Molly.
버섯을 먹고 환각제를 즐겼어요
Chemists--
we get the best stuff,
화학자, 우리는 최고의
물건을 가졌어요
직접 만들었으니까요
'cause we make it ourselves.
Charlotte was a nonstop party.
샬롯은 논스톱 파티였었죠
Until she wasn't?
중단할때까지는?
About a year ago,
1년전쯤,
her biological clock
started ticking, loud.
샬롯의 생체시계가 시끄럽게
울리기 시작했어요
She was talking about
wanting kids, getting married.
아이를 갖고 결혼을 하는 것에
대해 말하기 시작했어요
Which didn't interest you?
당신은 흥미가 없었던 것들이죠?
Well, how did Charlotte take it
when you broke things off?
헤어질 때, 샬롯이 어떻게 받아들였죠?
Not well, at first,
but then she got over it,
처음에는 힘들어했는데
극복했어요, 듣기로는
다른 남자를 만나서
'cause last I heard,
she'd met some guy,
결혼하기로 했대요
and they were gonna get married.
So, she got what she wanted,
and I did, too.
샬롯은 샬롯이 원하는대로
나는 내가 원하는대로
Win, win.
윈-윈이죠
You know her fianc챕's name?
약혼자의 이름을 알아요?
I was on something that night.
It's fuzzy.
그날 뭘 먹은 상태라서
헷갈리는데
Do you know the story behind
Charlotte's ?rache??/i> tattoo?
샬롯의 “rache”에 있는 사연 알아요?
I know it meant ?revenge.??
"복수"라는 뜻으로 알고 있어요
Aside from that, she didn't
really like to talk about it.
그 얘기는 별로 안해
Griffin.
그리핀
Excuse me?
뭐라고요?
Just came to me.
갑자기 떠올랐어요
New guy's first name-- Griffin.
약혼자의 이름, 그리핀이에요
What about his last name?
성은 알아요?
I don't think it ever came up.
그건 몰라요
You remember the newly-inked
tattoo on Charlotte's shoulder?
샬롯의 어깨에 있던 새 문신 기억하지?
A griffin.
Mm.
그리핀
If I'm not mistaken,
it was by the same artist
잘못 본 게 아니라면, 저 문신과
같은 문신가에게 받은거야
that did that tattoo.
문신 가게 이름이 뭐죠?
What was the name
of the tattoo shop?
Any progress?
진행상황은요?
Incremental, but significant.
진전이 있었고, 중요했어요
I was able to contact
Charlotte's tattoo artist, Aviv,
샬롯의 문신가인 아비브와 통화해서
who told me the tale of
Charlotte and her newest beau,
샬롯과 새 남친 그리핀에 대해 들었어요
Griffin.
가게에 같이 갔었군
So they went into
the shop together.
As people are wont to do
when they wish
문신 바늘로 사랑을 영원히
남기고 싶은 사람들이 가는 곳이죠
to immortalize their love
via the tattoo needle.
Never a good idea,
in my opinion.
절대 좋은 생각이 아니죠, 내 의견으로는
Life is far too fluid
for such mementos.
인생은 기념품을 남기기에는
너무 유동적이라서
내 배에 커다랗게 "모리아티"라고
써져있다고 상상해봐요
Imagine me with a giant
?Moriarty??across my stomach.
It would have said ?Irene??
but I take your point.
"아이린"이었겠지만
무슨 말인지는 알겠어요
Anyway, Charlotte's griffin
went on without a hitch,
어쨌든, 샬롯의 그리핀은
거침없이 그려졌지만
but when it was Griffin's turn,
things went awry.
남친 그리핀 쪽은, 틀어졌다고 해요
신청서는 적었지만
He filled out the release,
but no sooner
바늘을 꽂기도 전에
마음을 바꿨대요
had the needle gun started up
than he had a change of heart.
He chickened out.
In his defense,
겁먹었네
그의 입장에서는
he invoked his membership with
몰몬교도라고 주장했을지도 모르죠
the Church of Jesus Christ
of Latter-day Saints.
문신을 성스러운 인체의
더럽힘이라고 생각하니까
They view tattooing as
a defilement of the body temple.
샬롯이 실망스럽게도, 문신 가게를 나가서
To Charlotte's dismay,
he left the tattoo shop
다시 돌아오지 않았대요
uninked, never to return.
But he signed the release.
하지만 신청서에 서명이 남아있다면
If Aviv kept it, that means
그리핀의 이름 전체와 주소가 있겠죠
he has Griffin's full
name and address.
샬롯이 실종된지 1주일이 넘었을텐데
More than a week passed without
him reporting her missing,
난 이유를 알고 싶어요
and I would like to know why.
아비브가 서류를 뒤져서
찾는대로 알려주기로 했어요
Aviv is searching his files and
will get back to us presently.
Good. So we have
some time to talk.
잘됐네요. 그럼 우리
얘기할 시간이 있죠
About what?
무슨 얘기요?
About the AwayKay
next door
옆집의 AwayKay와
그 모든 일이 당신 잘못이라는 얘기
and how the whole
thing is your fault.
Hmm.
음
음? 그게 전부예요?
Hmm? That's it?
We chased some poor guy
out of his home,
우리가 집에서 쫓아내다시피 했는데
고작 할 말이 "음"이 전부라니
and all you can say is ?Hmm.??
You do see that this is not
my current e-mail address.
이건 지금 쓰는 이메일
주소가 아니라는거 알죠
So?
그래서요?
그래서, 처음 가비씨를
만났을 때, 난 중독상태였고
So, when I first met
Mr. Garby, I was on drugs,
여기서 오래 살 생각은 없었어요
didn't think I'd be
living here for very long.
새 친구를 만들 생각도 없어서
I had no desire to
make any new friends,
90년대 후반 이후로 사용하지
않는 이메일 주소를 줬어요
so I gave him
an e-mail address
I hadn't used since
the late '90s.
Instead of issuing his
grievances electronically,
전자우편으로 불만을 제기하는 대신
he could've just knocked
on our front door.
우리 집 문을 두드렸었어야죠
He was afraid of you.
Did I threaten him?
-당신을 어려워했어요
-내가 협박했대요?
You don't even remember
if you threatened him.
협박했다고 해도 기억 못하겠죠
약에 취했었으니까요
I was on drugs.
May I point out that by the time
Mr. Garby vacated his premises,
가비씨가 이사를 결정했을 때는
당신이 여기 들어와서 산 지
2년은 됐을 무렵이죠
you had been living here
for almost two years.
What, you're trying
to blame this on me?
내 탓으로 돌리려고 그래요?
I'm saying there's plenty
of blame to go around.
비난은 같이 받아야한다는 말이에요
You are the one who makes
all the noise. And you're the one
시끄럽게 하는 사람은 당신이잖아요
당신은 날 막지 않았어요. 왜? 내가 하는
작업이 중요하다는 걸 알고 있으니까
who never stops me. Why? Because
you know that the work I do
is important. It's for...
Okay, if you say
다수의 선을 위해서라고
말한다면, 때려줄 거예요
it's for the greater good,
I am gonna punch you.
You accompanied me once
런던에서 살던 내 집,
221B에 같이 갔었죠?
to my former residence
in London, 221B.
221A에 사는 사람에 대해
내가 말했었나요?
Did I ever tell you about
the people in 221A?
No.
아뇨
They didn't like having
me for a neighbor, either.
그들도 날 이웃으로
좋아하지 않았어요
What did you do?
I took care of it.
-어떻게 했어요?
-각별히 신경썼죠
What do you mean,
you took care of it?
무슨 뜻이에요? 신경썼다니?
It's the tattoo artist.
문신가예요
He's located Griffin's
personal information.
그리핀의 개인정보를 찾았대요
I couldn't have
killed Charlotte.
샬롯을 죽였을리가 없죠
난 샬롯을 사랑했어요
I loved her.
If you don't mind me saying so,
맘에 안들겠지만, 별로 안 어울려요
you seem like a...
you seem like an unlikely match.
I mean, Charlotte had
a checkered past.
샬롯은 다사다난한 과거가 있었죠
And sometimes she fell
back into old habits, but...
가끔 옛날 버릇으로 돌아갈 때도 있었지만
I wasn't perfect, either.
나도 완벽하지는 않았어요
We were working
to put all that behind us.
과거는 묻어놓기로 하고 함께 일했어요
How were you doing that
exactly?
정확히 뭘 했었죠?
We started going to services
together at the local ward.
지역교구에서 함께 일했어요
She was considering
converting.
인생의 변화도 고민했었죠
We were talking about
getting married, having kids.
우린 결혼과 아이에 대해 얘기했어요
실례할게요. 화장실 좀
Sir, excuse me.
I just need to...
bathroom.
I have to ask.
해야할 질문이 있어요
Charlotte has been dead
for over a week.
샬롯은 사망한지 1주일이 넘었는데
If you two were
so happy together,
두 사람이 그렇게 행복했다면
why didn't you
report her missing?
왜 실종신고를 하지 않았죠?
가끔 잠수를 탔어요
Sometimes she'd slip.
We'd fight.
다퉜을 때
보통 그런 일이 있을 때는, 한동안 사라져서
Usually when that happened,
she'd disappear for a while,
she wouldn't return my calls.
연락이 끊기고는 했어요
Once, she even went home
to Germany without telling me,
한 번은 저한테 말하지도 않고
독일 집으로 돌아간 적도 있었어요
so... I just thought it was
the same thing this time.
그래서, 이번에도 그런 줄 알았어요
And why did you think that?
왜 그렇게 생각했죠?
Did you two have a fight?
싸웠나요?
She wanted me
to get a tattoo.
샬롯이 저한테 문신을 받으라고 했어요
Uh... it just felt wrong,
so I said no.
내키지 않아서, 거절했어요
She got upset,
we argued, she left.
샬롯이 화를 냈고, 우린 말다툼 끝에
샬롯이 먼저 가버렸어요
I went by her place
a few days later, but, uh...
며칠 뒤에 집에 찾아갔지만
she didn't answer the door,
so...
나오지 않았어요, 그래서
I just decided
to give her some space.
더 시간을 줘야겠다고 생각했어요
And I was sure
she would come back eventually.
결국엔 돌아올 거라고 확신했었죠
항상 그랬으니까
She always had before.
What the heck? Hey.
뭐야, 저거? 이봐요
Hey! Hey, he can't
do that! Hey!
저런 짓을 하면 안돼죠, 이봐요!
뭐하는 짓이야? 무단침입이잖아!
Hey, what are you doing?!
That's breaking and entering!
Griffin, you seem like
an exemplary young man,
그리핀, 모범적인 청년으로 보였는데
so perhaps you'd
like to explain to me
뒷마당에 약물 제조실이 있는
이유를 설명해줄 수 있을까요
why you have a drug lab
in your backyard.
샬롯의 아이디어였어요
It was Charlotte's idea.
우리 둘 다 곤란한 상황이었어요
We were both struggling.
돈을 더 벌어야했죠
We needed to earn
some extra money.
그래서 불법 약물 제조를 시작했군요
So you began
to manufacture illegal drugs.
불법이 아니라, 위조약품이죠
Not illegal. Counterfeit.
구체적으로는 위조된
발기불능 알약이지
Counterfeit
erectile dysfunction pills,
to be specific.
주교가 뭐라고 말하려나?
What's your local bishop
going to have to say about that?
좋아하시지 않겠죠
He's not gonna like it.
하지만 제약회사들이 그 약
한알에 얼마를 받는지 아세요?
But do you know how much the
pharmaceutical companies charge
for just one of those pills?
40-50달러죠
$40 or $50.
대부분의 보험은 적용이 안돼요, 강도죠
And most insurance
won't cover them.
That's robbery.
그래서 당신과 샬롯이 큰 제약회사에
맞서싸우기로 결심했다구요
So you and Charlotte decided
to strike a blow
against Big Pharma.
우린 5달러도 안되는 가격으로
비슷한 약을 만들 수 있어요
We can make pills every bit
as good as the real thing
for under five dollars each.
유통업자에게 개당 10, 15달러에 팔면
Assuming you sold them
to a distributor
for ten, $15 a pill,
한 번에 10만달러는
you would have
raked in about...
쓸어모으겠네?
100 grand a batch?
하지만 둘 다 아직 세를 살고
Yet, the both of you
are still renting,
은행 계좌의 잔고가 늘지 않았던데?
there's no appreciable increase
in your bank accounts?
샬롯이 합법적으로 버는
What little money
that Charlotte made
약간의 돈은 제라켐 소송을 돕는
from her legitimate jobs
was going to the lawyers
변호사에게 들어가고 있었어요
handling her Zerakem lawsuit.
학자금 대출 상환과
And between paying off
your student loans
할머니의 의료비 때문에
and your grandmother's
medical bills,
당신도 거의 남은 게 없죠
you're barely getting by.
여기서 생기는 질문:
돈은 어디로 갔을까?
Which raises the question:
where did the money go?
I don't know.
난 몰라요
믿기 힘들어요
That's hard to believe.
당신은 화학자로, 샬롯의 목숨을 앗아간
You're a chemist, as well,
so you have the requisite skills
독소 추출에 필요한 기술이 있어요
to create the mycotoxin
that took her life.
I would never do that.
난 그런 짓 안했어요
그럼 돈의 행방을 말해봐요
Then explain
where the money went.
난 못해요
I can't.
누구한테 파는지도 몰라요
I don't even know
who we were selling to.
샬롯이 돈을 다루고,
Charlotte handled the
money, she dealt with
유통업자와의 거래,
다 알아서 했어요
the distributor,
all of it.
Whenever I asked,
내가 물어볼 때마다
계획대로 잘 되고 있다고 말해서
she said everything was
going according to plan,
여생이 보장됐을 줄 알았어요
and that we would be
set for life.
그것 뿐이에요
That's it.
그리고 넌 샬롯을 믿었어?
And you believed her?
오늘까지는요
I did until today.
But maybe she was putting
a happy face on things.
아마 행복한 척 했을지도 모르죠
You know, she did that
sometimes.
가끔은 그랬어요
Maybe... whoever she was
working with wasn't paying,
아마도 샬롯과 같이
일했던 사람이 돈을 안 줘서
밀어붙이다가 살해됐을지도 몰라요
she pushed, and they killed her.
I mean, I don't know.
저는 모른다는 말이에요
That's the only thing
that makes sense to me.
그런 얘기 밖에는 설명이 안돼요
Hey.
네
회계자문 보고서를 받았어요
Hey. So I just got a report
from the forensic accountant.
위조약물로 번 돈을
그리핀이 숨긴 흔적은 없고
There's no sign
Griffin's been hiding the money
from those counterfeit
E.D. pills,
집이나 연구실에서
and there's no evidence
in his home or his lab
버섯독 합성에 필요한 전구물질을
that he's handled
the precursors you'd need
다룬 증거도 없어요
to synthesize
the mushroom poison.
그럼 그리핀의 진술이 다 확인됐네요?
So his story checks out?
네, 위약 제조 혐의는 있지만
Yeah. We're holding him
살해범은 아니에요
on the drug charges, but
I don't think he's our killer.
샬롯의 유통업자를 알아내는
일은 잘 되고 있어요?
So, I don't suppose you
and Sherlock have had any luck
identifying Charlotte's
distributor?
셜록 말로는 계획이 있대요
Well, Sherlock said
he had a plan.
식료품점에 들러서 가는 길이라..
I just took a break to get some
groceries, so I'm almost...
마커스, 내가 다시 전화할게요
Marcus, I'm gonna
have to call you back.
Tell me you did not start that fire.
I did not start that fire.
-당신이 불내지 않았다고 말해요
-내가 불내지 않았어요
AwayKay 문제는 당신이
신경쓰겠다고 말했잖아요
You said that you were
gonna take care
of the AwayKay problem.
민속 공예였어요
Through folk art.
특히
Specifically,
전기톱 조각이요
chain saw sculpting.
One uses a chain saw
to artfully sculpt
나무 기둥을 전기톱으로 조각하는 것으로
곰이나 독수리를 만들어요
entire tree trunks
into a bear perhaps
or an eagle.
질이 낮고 매우 시끄러워요
All rather kitsch
and extremely loud.
창고에서 전기톱을 찾아서
I'd retrieved my chain saw
from storage,
기름칠하고 있었어요
and I was in the process
of oiling it
화재가 시작됐을 때는
when that fire broke out.
당신 알리바이는 전기톱 기름칠이었다구요
So your alibi is that you were
oiling your chain saw.
221A와의 문제 해결 방법이었어요?
Is this how you solved
your problem at 221A?
민속 공예?
Folk art?
221A를 샀어요
I bought 221A.
현재 상황과 똑같이 할 수도 있지만
I was quite willing to do the
same in our current situation,
전기톱이 첫걸음으로 보였어요
but the chain saw seemed
like a logical first step.
Well, I am sorry
that I accused you of arson.
미안하지만 난 당신이 방화범인 것 같아요
내가 용의자였죠
Well, I was
the obvious suspect.
The fire marshal believes
that the fire was
소방관은 화재는 전기에서 시작됐고,
앰프에서 시작됐다고 했어요
electrical in nature, started
by a faulty amplifier.
사고죠
An accident.
다른 소식은, 여러 곳의
In other news,
I've placed express orders
온라인 약국에서 발기부전
치료제를 배송주문했어요
for erectile dysfunction
medication
from several dozen
online pharmacies.
샬롯과 그리핀이 제조한 약의 양으로 봐선,
Given the volume of pills
Charlotte and Griffin
were manufacturing,
it seems like
대부분의 유통 과정이라고 보였으니까요
the most likely route
for distribution.
위약과 진품의 미묘한 차이를 봐요
Note the subtle difference
between the counterfeits
and the real thing.
샬롯과 그리핀의 약이
파란색이 약간 부족해요
Charlotte and Griffin's pills
are a little less blue.
같은 농도를 가진 약을 찾는다면
Hmm. If I can find pills
in the same shade,
온라인 약국에 상품을 제공하는
I might be able to identify
유통업자를 찾을 수 있어요
which online pharmacy they were
using to distribute their wares.
Okay. So I inadvertently sold
some counterfeit medicine.
그래요. 제가 부주의로
위조약을 팔았네요
경고인가요, 과태료?
We talking a warning, a fine?
별로 심각하게 생각하지 않네요
You don't seem
very concerned.
제 입장에서는 과태료는
In my line of work,
fines are just
사업비의 일부일 뿐이죠
part of the cost
of doing business.
살인은 어때요?
What about murder?
그것도 사업 전략 중 하나인가요?
Is that part
of your business model as well?
누가 살해됐어요?
Who got murdered?
샬롯 코니그
Charlotte Konig.
그 약을 만든 여자였어요
The woman who
made those pills.
독살됐어
She was poisoned.
당신은 면허 약사죠, 퐁씨
You're a licensed pharmacist,
Mr. Fong.
생화학 실험실도 잘 알고 있겠죠
I assume you know your way
around a biochem lab.
내가 왜 살롯을 죽이겠어요?
Why would I kill Charlotte?
좋은 물건을 만들어주는데
She made a great product.
샬롯의 유통업자라는 건 인정하는군요?
So you admit to being
her distributor?
네, 맞아요. 하지만 죽이지는 않았어요
Yeah, fine,
but I didn't kill her.
그럼 돈은 어딨어요?
So where's the money?
무슨 돈이요?
What money?
샬롯의 약에 지불해야했던 돈
The money
that you should've paid her
수십만달러도 넘을텐데
for her product-- hundreds of
thousands of dollars.
내가 줘야할 돈은 한푼도
빼지않고 다 줬어요
I paid Charlotte
every dime that I owed her.
부동산으로 지불했어요
I just did it in real estate.
보세요
Look.
뉴워크의 부동산을 사서
She had me buy up a bunch
of rundown properties in Newark,
일종의 비밀 보험으로
쓰는 신탁에 넣었어요
put them in a trust
where she was a secret
sole beneficiary.
Those are all
interest-only loans.
모두 이자상환 대출이네요
내가 이자를 내면
더 많은 물건과 교환했어요
And I pay the interest,
in exchange for more product.
But I don't think she was gonna
하지만 샬롯이 오래 갖고
있을 것 같지는 않았어요
hold on to the properties
for long.
이익을 남기고 팔기 위한
거래를 하려는 것 같았지만
I got a feeling
she was working on a deal
to unload them at a profit, but
she never told me the details.
자세한 얘기는 못 들었어요
저 부동산 지도가 있어요?
You got a map
of these properties?
네
Sure.
Those are all near
모두 제라켐 공장 근처네요
Zerakem facilities.
드디어 우리가 샬롯의 복수를 알아냈어요
I think we've finally found
Charlotte's revenge.
샬롯의 부동산의 위치는 여기죠
Note the location
of Charlotte's properties here.
제라켐 공장의 2곳과 맞닿아있어요
All of them bordering
these two Zerakem facilities.
그렇군요
I see.
제라켐은 여기에 3개의 공장이 있어요
Now, Zerakem has three
facilities in the area, right?
2개는 안쪽이고 하나는
These two, further inland,
and this main one here
퍼세익 강 옆에 있어요
by the Passaic River.
각각 1/4마일정도 떨어져있어요
These are separated by a little
over a quarter of a mile.
그렇죠?
Correct?
맞아요
Correct.
이 거리가 중요한 이유를
설명해줄 수 있어요?
Right. Could
you explain
to us why that distance
is important?
For these facilities to be
considered separate entities
환경보호국에 의해 개별
시로 인정받으려면
by the EPA,
they have to be more than
1/4마일 이상 떨어져있어야해요
a quarter of a mile apart.
더 가까우면
If they're any closer,
they count as one facility
오염단속에서 1개로 세기 때문이죠
for the sake of
pollution regulation.
1개의 큰 공장은 3개의 작은 공장보다
And one larger facility
is subject to much more
stringent regulation
than three smaller ones.
엄격한 단속의 대상이 되겠죠
Mm-hmm.
Now, according to plans
제라켐이 시에 제출한 계획서에 다르면
Zerakem's filed with the city,
they plan to implement
샬롯의 생체연료 공정은
이 공장에서 시행될 계획이죠
Charlotte's biofuel process
at this plant here.
해조류 탱크는 여기,
공정은 여기
Algae tanks here,
processing here.
문제만 빼면요
Except there's a problem.
확장에 의해 공장들의 간격이 좁아지면
By expanding,
you close the gap
between the facilities,
which will trigger
환경보호국의 엄격한 단속을 유인하게 되고
much more stringent
EPA regulations
매년 수백만달러가 들어가겠죠, 만약
that will cost you
millions per year, unless...
이 두 공장을 내륙쪽으로
확장하지 않으면
We expand these two facilities
- further inland.
- Mm.
환경보호국의 간격 측정은
Because the EPA measures
the distance between facilities
경계에서 경계가 아니라
중심에서 중심까지니까
not from border to border,
but from center to center.
이 공장들을 이렇게 확장하면
So if you expand
these facilities like so...
제라켐은 과태료 지불이나 업그레이드 없이
And Zerakem can continue
to pollute at their old levels
without paying fines
or making upgrades.
원래 레벨을 유지할 수 있어요
샬롯이 당신들보다 먼저 알았어요
Charlotte figured
that out before you did.
길을 막았어요
She roadblocked you.
제라켐이 생체연료 공정에 지불해야
할 금액만큼 바가지를 씌울 생각이었죠
She was trying
to gouge Zerakem
into paying her the money
that she believed she was owed
for her biofuel process.
시세보다 1500만달러 이상
$15 million above market--
신탁이 부동산 가격으로
요구한 금액이었어요
that's what the trust that holds
these properties was demanding.
이제 샬롯이 죽었어요
Except now Charlotte is dead.
우리가 알기로는, 상속자가 없으니
As far as we can tell,
she has no heirs,
은행에서 담보권을 행사하고
so the banks will foreclose
on her properties,
제라켐은 적정 시장가격으로
매입할 수 있겠군요
and Zerakem will be able
to purchase them
- at fair market value.
- Thus saving millions
수백만달러를 아끼고
당신들을 괴롭혔던 잔소리꾼도 없애고
and avoiding paying off a gadfly
who's been making you suffer.
살인의 동기처럼 들리는군요
Sounds like a motive
for murder to me.
난 제라캠에서만 내 인생을 바쳤어요
I have worked my entire
adult life at Zerakem.
회사가 할 수 있는 일에 대한
I've never
believed the rumors
소문은 믿지 않았어요
about what the company
is capable of.
실제 범법행위의 증거를 본 적이 없었어요
I-I've never seen any real
evidence of any wrongdoing.
하지만 만약 샬롯 코니그가
신탁의 배후였고, 이제 죽었다면
But if Charlotte Konig
is behind the trust
and now she's dead...
사람을 죽이는 회사를
위해 일하지 않겠어요
I won't work for a company
that murders people.
뭘 원하죠?
What do you need?
You're offering to cooperate?
협조하겠다는 겁니까?
제라켐을 전소시켜버리겠어요
I'm offering to burn Zerakem
to the ground.
미스 팰이 전부 줬어요
Miss Pal gave
us everything.
뉴 저지 확장에 대해
제라켐에서 썼던 모든 메모와 이메일
Every memo that anyone
at Zerakem ever wrote
about the New Jersey
expansion, every e-mail.
유용하게 쓸 수 있는 유일한 방법은
The only way any of
it would be useful
수천개의 새장 밑바닥에 깔려있어요
is lining the bottom of
several thousand birdcages.
오, 아무 것도 못 찾았군요
Oh, you're not
finding anything.
훌륭한 거래를 찾았어요
I found a great deal.
이 모든 것들은, 십중팔구는
All of it indicates that,
in all likelihood,
제라켐이 샬롯을 죽이지 않았다는 증거죠
Zerakem did not kill
Charlotte Konig.
겨우 2일 전에 고위 경영진들은
As recently as two days ago,
the senior management were
instructing their lawyers
변호사들에게 부동산 신탁의
to attempt to identify
배후를 알아내라고 했어요
the principals
behind the land trust.
샬롯인 줄 몰랐군요
They didn't know
it was Charlotte.
몰랐어요. 알았더라도
They did not,
and even if they had,
얻는 이익은 없었어요
they would not have been able
to profit from it.
1500만달러를 아낄 수 있잖아요
The company would have
saved $15 million.
하지만 그렇더라도 특별 보너스를
받는 사람은 아무도 없어요
But no one at the company
was in line
for a specific bonus
over the deal.
1500만달러 아껴도
제라켐 주식가격에는
The $15 million savings
would not have moved
전혀 영향을 미치지 않아요
Zerakem's stock price one iota.
스톡 옵션은 회사가 성공했을 때만
경영자가 받을 수 있어요
And stock options are
the only way the
executives could share
in the corporation's
success.
그러니 제라켐 자체에는 동기가 있지만
So while Zerakem itself
has motive,
회사의 사람 중에는
아무도 동기가 없어요
no human being
at the company does.
그럼 다시 돌아가야겠네요
So we're back
to the drawing board.
Mm-hmm.
What is it?
뭐죠?
트렌트 가비에게 온 이메일이에요
Uh, it's an e-mail
from Trent Garby.
보험회사로부터 화재 보상을 거절당했대요
He's saying that
his insurance company
is refusing
to pay out on the fire,
because he was using his
property for short-term rentals.
집을 단기 임대로 제공했기 때문에요
호텔로 임대했기 때문에
So it was technically a hotel.
보상범위에 해당하지 않는대요
He doesn't have
the right coverage.
잘됐네. 플랜B로 넘어갈 수 있어요
That's good. We can
carry out plan B,
플랜 221A,
매입하라. 이번엔 깎아서
aka plan 221A: buy the
place, now at a discount.
냉정하다고 말할 수도 있지만
I would say
that you're a callous jerk,
연락을 한 이유가 있어요
but that's actually
why he's reaching out.
우리랑 맨처음 도착한 이웃 명단을 줬대요
He's giving us and the other
neighbor first crack.
그 이메일 전달해줘요
아침에 조사해볼게
Forward me the e-mail, I'll
investigate it in the morning.
약간의 잘못도 느껴지지 않아요?
Don't you feel even a little bit bad?
About?
-뭐에 대해서요?
-트렌트의 이사는 우리 잘못이잖아요
I mean, it's our fault
that Trent moved out.
아직도 옆집에 살고 있었다면
If he was still
living next door,
보험에서 문제가 되진 않았을거예요
he wouldn't have this issue
with his insurance.
그게 세상의 이치예요, 왓슨
That's the way
of the world, Watson.
우리는 불가항력이었고
그는 움직이는 물체였어요
We were an irresistible force,
he was a movable object.
그가 움직였어요
He moved.
죄책감 느끼고 싶다면
If you want to feel
bad about something,
우린 5시간 전부터 샬롯의 범인에 대해
feel bad about the fact that
we're no closer to identifying
전혀 밝혀내지 못하고 있어요
Charlotte's killer
than we were five hours ago.
What if Charlotte
wasn't the target?
샬롯이 목표가 아니었다면요?
샬롯이 발렌타인에게
버섯을 나눠줄 것을
What if the killer knew
that she was gonna share
범인이 알고 있었다면요?
her mushrooms with Ballantine?
새 용의자가 있어요?
You have a new suspect in mind?
원래 있었던 용의자예요
Old one, actually.
알스턴 하퍼를 너무 빨리
제외시켰는지도 몰라요
Maybe we gave up too quickly
on Alston Harper.
그와 발렌타인이 화해했다고 말했지만
I mean, he said he and
Ballantine buried the hatchet,
누가 알아요?
but who knows?
Maybe we should take
a look at him again,
다시 살펴보면
우리가 놓친 게 있을지도 몰라요
see if we missed anything.
알스턴 C 하퍼
Alston C. Harper.
샬롯의 “rache”문신이요
Charlotte's ?rache??/i> tattoo.
다른 글자에 비해 R과 E가
더 진했던 게 기억나요
I seem to remember the ?R??br>and the ?E??incrementally darker
처음에는 디자인인 줄 알았는데
than the other letters; first,
I thought that was by design.
다른 이유가 있다면요?
What if there was
another reason?
당신이 맞다고 생각해요
I think you're right.
하퍼를 다시 조사해볼 가치가 있어요
Harper is worth
looking at again,
하지만 발렌타인을 노려서가 아니라
but not because he wanted
to kill Ballantine,
샬롯을 죽이려고 했기 때문이에요
because he wanted
to kill Charlotte.
하퍼가 샬롯을 왜요?
What would Harper have
against Charlotte?
남자가 헤어진 부인에게 하는 짓이 뭘까요?
What does any man have
against his ex?
A.C.H.
Alston C. Harper
Alston C. Harper.
Uh, class doesn't start
for another 15 minutes.
15분동안 강의는 시작되지 않아요
코르티졸 강의 들으러 오셨나봐요
I assume you're here
for the lecture on cortisol.
아뇨, 개인의 싸움 또는
회피 반응을 보러 왔어요
No, we're here to see
the fight-or-flight response
in person.
당신은 샬롯 코니그 살해
혐의로 체포될 겁니다
You're being arrested
for the murder
of Charlotte Konig.
Why would I murder
my former grad student?
내가 왜 대학원생이었던 애를 죽여요?
Not just a student, your wife.
그냥 학생이 아니라 아내죠
Apparently, one of
the stupid things you did
환각제에 취해서 저질렀던
멍청한 짓 중 하나가
샬롯과의 결혼이었죠
when you were on hallucinogens
was marry Charlotte.
알스톤 C 하퍼와 샬롯 코니그의 결혼 증명서로
Marriage certificate
for Alston C. Harper
and Charlotte Konig,
4년전 독일 바트 톨즈에서 발행됐어요
issued four years ago
in Bad Tolz, Germany.
There's no divorce decree
on file,
이혼판정이 없으니
샬롯 사망 당시 법적으로
so legally you and Charlotte
were still husband and wife
당신과 샬롯은 부부였어요
at the time of her death.
우린 별거중이었어요
We were estranged.
조와 조의 열린 생활과 끝냈을 때
When I made my break
from Joe and his...
샬롯과도 더이상 지낼 수 없었어요
expanded lifestyle, I couldn't
be with Charlotte anymore.
내게는 좋지 않았어요
It wasn't good for me.
샬롯은 원하지 않았죠?
She didn't like
that though, did she?
She was still in love with you.
아직 당신을 사랑했었으니까
어깨 뒤에 새긴 당신의
이니셜이 곤혹스러웠겠죠
I mean, she'd already
gone to the trouble
of having your initials tattooed
on the back of her shoulder.
After you broke her heart,
당신과 헤어지고 나서
she added an ?R??and an ?E,??
“A.C.H.” 에
“R”과 “E”를 추가해서
“RACHE”를 만들었어요
turning ?A.C.H.??into ?rache.??/i>
복수의 대상은 당신이었어요
You were the one she wanted
to take revenge against.
샬롯이 이혼을 미루려고 했었죠?
She tried to hold you up
on the divorce, right?
당신 책에 나온 공정의
상당부분을 주장했어요
Claimed a chunk of
the proceeds from your books.
결국, 당신의 연구를 도왔던거죠
After all, she helped you
do the research.
그래서 책을 없앴어요, 샬롯을 밀어내려고
That's why you had them pulled,
to spite her.
전부 추측이죠
This is all conjecture.
아닙니다
No, it's not.
최근 사립탐정을 고용했죠
You recently hired
a private detective,
드웨인 위버
one Duane Weaver.
Fortunately for us,
다행히도
사립탐정은 법적으로 고객의
비밀유지 의무가 없어
P.I.s are not legally bound
by client privilege.
의뢰받은 일에 대해 경찰에게
자유롭게 진술할 수 있어요
They're quite free to discuss
their cases with the police.
몇달전 샬롯이 이혼을 결정했다고
하더군요. 아무 조건없이
Duane told us Charlotte
approached you a few months ago
and finally offered a divorce,
no strings attached.
의구심이 들어 드웨인을 시켜 조사를 했죠
You got suspicious and hired him
to look into her.
불법이 아니오
That's not illegal.
드웨인은 일을 꽤 잘했어요
Duane's more than competent.
He uncovered Charlotte's
real estate holdings
샬롯의 부동산 취득과
and her attempts
to strong-arm Zerakem
제라켐에 바가지를 씌우려는
시도도 밝혀냈어요
into a generous buyout.
That's why she was
마침내 당신과 이혼을
결심한 이유였죠
finally willing
to grant you the divorce.
사랑에 빠졌고, 부자가 됐고
She was in love,
she was about to get rich;
더이상 복수를 하지 않아도 됐어요
she didn't need
to seek revenge anymore.
당신이 복수를 원했어요
Only, you wanted
revenge against her,
발목을 붙잡고 있던
시간에 대한 보상으로
for the years she'd held
your feet to the flames.
복수도 하고 부자가 될 방법을 알아냈죠
You realized
that you could have it
and get rich in the process.
샬롯의 법적인 배우자로
As Charlotte's legal husband,
you would inherit
사망시 모든 재산을 상속받게 돼요
all of her properties
when she died.
그 후에 제라켐에 팔 수도 있고
Then you could
sell them to Zerakem.
You have no evidence.
아무 증거도 없잖소
드웨인이 거짓말을 한거야
Duane is lying.
영장을 받을 정도는 됐어요
We have enough for a warrant.
이미 당신의 대학 연구실을 조사했어요
We already searched
your on-campus lab.
뭘 찾았을까요
Guess what we found.
죽음의 모자 독을 합성했지
You manufactured
synthetic death cap poison.
기구에서 잔여물을 발견했어
We found residue
in your equipment.
You poisoned Charlotte,
and then you inadvertently
당신은 샬롯을 독살하고
우연히 발렌타인과 5명의
무고한 사람들을 살해했어
killed Ballantine
and five innocent people.
????
안녕하세요
Hi.
내 제안을 들었나보군
I take it you
got my offer.
Here to talk terms
or just gloat?
계약하러 아니면 그냥 비웃으려고?
선물드리려고 왔어요
Bearing gifts, actually.
If you can
prove arson,
방화를 증명할 수 있으면
화재에 대한 보험을
받을 수 있어야해요
you should be able to collect
insurance for the fire.
So... this should do it.
이게 도움이 될 거예요
Pictures of a van?
봉고차 사진?
저희 보안카메라에 찍혔어요
Captured by
our security cameras.
손님이 집을 나갔을 때인데, 화재 발생
This van was parked
outside our brownstone
2시간 전쯤 저희 집 밖에
주차되어 있었어요
a few hours before the fire,
when your guests were out.
하지만 동네 주민 누구도 그날
전기기사를 부르지 않았어요
But no one in the neighborhood
hired an electrician that day.
그리고 사실, 이 전기기사는 부띠끄 호텔인
And in fact, this electrician
works almost exclusively
'포인트 센터'에서만 독점적으로 일해요
for the Point Center,
a boutique hotel.
오, 알아. 2블럭 밑에 있지
Oh, I know it; it's a
couple of blocks down.
In fact, the owner of
the hotel has tried
호텔 주인이 그 주변의 AwayKay 를
전부 폐업시키려고 했지
to get every AwayKay in the
neighborhood to shut down.
어제도 시도했어요
Yesterday he tried again.
He said that your fire proved
화재로 인해 AwayKays가 안전하지 않고
보험이 안된다는 걸
증명했다고 말했어요
that AwayKays were
unsafe and underinsured.
He hired an electrician
to start the fire?
호텔 주인이 전기기사를
고용해서 불을 질렀다고?
I spoke to
the arson investigators.
제가 화재 조사관에게 말했어요
The electrician is in custody,
전기기사는 이미 잡혔고
호텔 주인도 오늘 중으로
구속되어야해요
and the hotel's owner should be
in jail by the end of the day.
보험금만 받으면
Well, if I get an
insurance settlement,
재건할 수 있어. 팔지 않아도 돼
I-I can rebuild, I-I
don't have to sell.
AwayKay를 다시 열수도 있지만
You can also reopen
your AwayKay,
다시 이사를 오셨으면 해요
but we would much rather
you moved back in.
Robert Frost said that fences
make good neighbors.
로버트 프로스는 울타리가
좋은 이웃을 만든다고 했어요
하지만 그 때는 방음장치가
없었기 때문일걸요
But maybe that's
because there wasn't
sound-dampening
insulation back then.
재건축을 하실 때, 저희가
뒤늦은 집들이 선물로
Since you are rebuilding anyway,
we can have it installed for you
설치해드릴 수도 있어요
as a belated housewarming gift.
당신은 더 조용한 집,
So a quieter home for you,
저희에겐 이해해주는 이웃이 생기겠죠
and a neighbor who knows
what he's getting into for us.
날 알지도 못하잖소
You don't even know me.
We'd like to.
저희가 원해요
All right.
좋아
When I get the insurance
settlement, I'll let you know.
보험금을 받으면 알려주리다
This is from Sherlock.
이건 셜록의 선물이에요
He wants you to know that bees
can be good neighbors, too.
벌도 좋은 이웃이 될 수
있다는 걸 알아주시래요
????
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man